Luciano Augusto Marchezan de Paula

Linz - Austria
lucianomarchp@gmail.com
Web-site:
https://lucianomarchezan.github.
io/

SUMMARY

Has experience in Computer Science, focusing on Software Engineering. Graduated as Software Engineer at Universidade Federal do Pampa (UNIPAMPA) – Campus Alegrete. Finished Master Degree in Software Engineering at Universidade Federal do Pampa – Campus Alegrete in 2020. Worked for 5 years at the Laboratory of Empirical Studies in Software Engineering (LESSE) as a researcher on the topics of Software Product Lines with a focus on Re-engineering.

Currently, a Ph.D. student at the Institute of Software Systems
Engineering (ISSE) at Johannes Kepler University Austria, supervised by
Prof. Dr. Alexander Egyed. The current research includes Model-Driven
Software Engineering, Automated Software Engineering, Software Reuse,
and Empirical Software Engineering.

EDUCATION

Johannes Kepler University (JKU), Linz, Austria — *Phd in Computer Science*

MAR 2021- PRESENT

Supervisor: Alexander Egyed Current Project: Consistency Maintenance Engineering in Collaborative Environments

Universidade Federal do Pampa, UNIPAMPA, Brazil — Professional Master Studies In Software Engineering

MAR 2019 - JUL 2020

Supervisor: Elder de Macedo Rodrigues.

Final Project: PAxSPL: A generic framework to support the planning of

SPL reengineering. Available online at:

https://repositorio.unipampa.edu.br/handle/riu/5230

Universidade Federal do Pampa, UNIPAMPA, Brazil — Bachelors In Software Engineering

MAR 2012 - DEC 2018

Supervisor: Elder de Macedo Rodrigues.

Final Project: PAxSPL: a Feature Retrieval Process for Software Product Line Re-engineering. Available online at:

http://dspace.unipampa.edu.br:8080/jspui/bitstream/riu/3335/1/Luciano

Marchezan%202018.pdf

SKILLS

Research skills developed during 7+ years of research experience at the Laboratory of Empirical Studies in Software Engineering and the Institute of Software Systems Engineering.

Programming skills acquired from many courses during graduation and masters as well as professional experience in: JAVA, PHP, JS, Dart, HTML, CSS, Python and C#.

Skills related to development frameworks: Laravel, Flutter, Firebase, Primefaces, Eclipse Modeling Framework.

Modeling skills: UML, ER, feature models, product line architecture.

AWARDS

2022 - Best paper from the ICSSP/ICGSE Conference

2021 - Best Master Thesis from the CTD-ES (Brazil)

2019 - Best paper from the Masters/PhD track - ERES 2019, III Software Engineering Regional School.

PROJECTS

DesignSpace: a cloud infrastructure for engineering knowledge and service — Ph.D. Project

SEP 2021 - PRESENT

Project website: https://isse.jku.at/designspace/

PAxSPLv4: a Tool-Supported Re-engineering Process for SPL. — Masters Project

JAN 2019 - JUL 2020

PAxSPLv4, improves aspects of earlier versions, including a web-based supporting tool. Project website:

https://github.com/HestiaProject/PAxSPL

Thoth: A Web-based Tool to Support Systematic Reviews — Research Project

OCT 2019 - JUL 2020

Development of an open-source web-based tool for supporting Systematic Reviews. Results available at:

https://ieeexplore.jeee.org/abstract/document/8870160/

Model Based Testing (MBT) — Research Project

NOV 2016 - JUL 2020

Investigate new models, tools, and processes that may support and automate the MBT process. Results available at:

https://digital-library.theiet.org/content/journals/10.1049/iet-sen.2015.0

Domain Specific Languages For Modeling Performance Tests — Research Project

MAR 2017 - JUL 2020

Development of two DSLs (graphical and textual) for modeling performance tests for web applications. Publication:

https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10664-020-09872-1

NutrientesBio — Research Project

OCT 2018 - MAY 2019

App for android devices with the goal to provide pedagogical support in elementary school science classes.. Website:

https://github.com/lucianoMarchezan/nutrientesBio

2019 - Student with the most outstanding performance in the Software Engineering Masters Program at Universidade Federal do Pampa.

2018- Student with the most outstanding performance of the Graduates from the Software Engineering Undergraduate Course at Universidade Federal do Pampa awarded by the Brazilian Computer Society.

2018- Student with the most outstanding performance in the Software Engineering Undergraduate Course at Universidade Federal do Pampa.

2016 - Student with the most outstanding performance in the Software Engineering Undergraduate Course at Universidade Federal do Pampa.

2014- Dean's List Certificate, Illinois Institute of Technology School of Applied Technology.

2014- Recognition Award for IPRO Day Track 5, SAT/INTM Brazilian Scientific Mobility Projects at Illinois Institute of Technology School of Applied Technology.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native speaker.

English: Comprehends Well, Speaks Well, Reads Well, Writes Well (TOEFL-IBT Score: 105).

Spanish: Comprehends Reasonably, Speaks Little, Reads Reasonably, Writes Little.

PAxSPL: A feature retrieval process for software product line reengineering — Final Graduation Project

MAR 2017 - JUL 2018

PAxSPL, a process that provides support for SPL reengineering. Results available at: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/spe.2707

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Johannes Kepler University, Linz, Austria— University Assistant

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

Lecturing and assisting with courses for the Bachelor of Computer Science and the Master in Software Engineering at the Institute of Software Systems Engineering. Institute web-site: https://isse.jku.at/

Johannes Kepler University, Linz, Austria — Researcher

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

Researching and development solutions for the field of verification of systems and software at the Institute of Software Systems Engineering. Institute web-site: https://isse.jku.at/

Capataz, Alegrete, RS - Brazil — Part Time

FEB 2019 - PRESENT

Software Engineer developing web and mobile apps for managing cattle at ranches. Company web-site https://capataz.com.br/

EletroVirtual, Alegrete, RS - Brazil — Part Time

JUL 2019 - JUL 2020

Software Engineer developing web and mobile apps for managing the company's services and finances. Company web-site: https://eletrovirtual.com.br/

Porthal Sistemas*, Alegrete, RS - Brazil — Internship

AUG 2017 - NOV 2017

Software Engineer internship working on systems developed inside the company such as ICodeERP. *Company changed its name to AGRARE (https://www.agrare.com.br/)

GreenWays2Go, Chicago, Illinois - USA — Summer *Internship*

IUN 2014 - AUG 2014

A web platform was developed, including web pages. Company web-site: http://greenways2go.com/